Guide to the John N. Warfield papers, 1931-2009
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
John N. Warfield papers
1931-2009
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
John N. Warfield, 1925-2009
C0016
98 linear feet (99 boxes)
The John N. Warfield papers consist of materials from Warfield's long and distinguished career, including papers authored and co-authored by Warfield, presentations, videotapes, audiotapes, and correspondence.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Alternative Form Available
There are numerous documents from the collection, including video, that are available through.
Acquisition Information
Donated in 1999 and subsequent donations.
Biographical Information
John N. Warfield was educated in mathematics and electrical engineering. He worked in eight universities and in three industries. Early on, he concentrated on teaching but later focused his energies on research. His publications include books on computers and complexity reflecting his development of systems science, incorporating a system for managing complexity. Understanding complexity, Warfield discovered, depended on a theory of thought about thought merged with empirical evidence of human behavioral pathologies and the application of design concepts in groups. Warfield's scientific research emphasized adherence to established criteria for scientific work, drawing inspiration from numerous well-known scholars, most especially Charles S. Peirce. Other scholars adopted his theories and methodologies, applying his research results in many locations and on many projects, invariably involving complexity. Their work provided ample and significant empirical evidence to support hypotheses and theories developed through his scientific endeavors, verifying the theoretical foundations of his scientific investigation. He also applied the results of his research to all levels of education with special attention paid to the shortcomings of higher education and requirements for adapting it to modern necessities.
Scope and Content
The John N. Warfield papers consist of materials from Warfield's long and distinguished career, including papers authored and co-authored by Warfield, presentations, videotapes, audiotapes, and correspondence.
Series 1 consists of textual materials such as unpublished papers, correspondence, lecture notes, and project reports. These materials were donated between 1999 and 2006.
Series 2 is comprised of audiovisual materials including filmed lectures and workshops.
Series 3 contains transparencies and other teaching materials.
Series 4 consists of materials deposited after January 2007.
List of Acronyms in the John N. Warfield Collection
AAAS - American Association for the Advancement of Science
ACAC - Academic Computing Advisory Committee
ADH - Advanced Decision Handling, Inc.
AI - Artificial Intelligence
AIO - Americans for Indian Opportunity
AIIM - American Institute for Interactive Management
AIO - Americans for Indian Opportunity
AIS - Association for Integrative Studies
APT - Analytical Power Train (Ford Motor Company)
ASC - American Society for Cybernetics
C3P - Computer Aided Design, Computer Aided Manufacturing, Computer Aided Engineering, Product Information Management
CAD - Computer Aided Design
CAM - Computer Aided Manufacturing
CAE - Computer Aided Engineering
CIM - Center for Interactive Management
CIMI - Cent for Interactive Management India
CIT - Center for Innovative Technology
DSMC - Defense Systems Management College
FMC - Ford Motor Company
IASIS - Institute for Advanced Study in Integrative Sciences
IIT - Institute for Information Technology
IM - Interactive Management
IPAC - International Programs Committee
ISM - Interpretive Structural Modeling
ISSS - International Society for Systems Science
ITESM - Instituto Technologico y de Estudios Superiores de Monterrey
ITRC - Information Technology Research Council
NCMS - National Centre for Manufacturing Services
NGT - Nominal Group Technique
NMFS - National Marine Fisheries Service
NSF - National Science Foundation
OPMS - One Page Management Systems
ORSA - Operations Research Society of America
PIM - Product Information Management
PIP - Process Improvement Plan
SGSR - Society for General Systems Research
TCS - Tata Consulting Services
TIPP - The Institute of Public Policy
UNI - University of Northern Iowa
Arrangement
Organized into four series:
Series 1: Textual Material, 1943-2001 (Boxes 1-51)
Series 2: Audiovisual Materials, 1978-2000 (Boxes 51-71)
Series 3: Transparencies and Other Teaching Materials, 1979-2005 (Boxes 72-88)
Series 4: Additional Materials Deposited After 1/2007, 1931-2009 (Boxes 89-99)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives created a web exhibit on the life and work of John Warfield called.
Index Terms
Persons:
Warfield, John N.
Corporate Names:
Center for Interactive Management.; George Mason University. Institute for Advanced Study in the Integrative Sciences.
Subjects:
Complexity (Philosophy); Education, Higher.; Interactive Management.; Policy Sciences.; Problem Solving.; Social Science--Methodology.; System Design.
Contents List
- Series 1: Textual Materials, 1943-2001; (51 boxes)
  The documents in this series consist of a number of published and unpublished papers spanning Warfield's entire career. There are also correspondence, lecture notes, and project reports. Materials were donated before 2006.
  - Research History Material V.2, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Research History Materials V.2, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Research History Materials V.1, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Proposed Research Program on Community Design, December 15, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Requests for Publication, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Administrative Papers [Battelle/UVA], undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Design of Transient Organizations Interim Reports #1,2,3, & 4, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Academy for Contemporary Problems, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Workshops, Schedules, & notes: Battlle, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Work Assessment Example: Battelle, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Concept of Interdisciplinary Team, October 2, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Battelle Meetings, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Learning System Theory, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Rome Special World Conference on Future Research, September 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The Role of Battelle Planning Service Activity in Battelle [Dayton, Scott, & Warfield], July 10, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - A Perspective on the Societal Problem Studies in the Bi Science & Human Program, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Technical Discussion of the Science Base Project. Interpretive Structural Modeling, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Research Future 2,3 & 4 Quarters 1973 & 1 and 2 Quarters OF 1974, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - A View of Science & Human Affairs Programs, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Group Process& Interdisciplinary Work, A Report on Large City Design Team, September 6, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Seminar on Urban Problems: A Report on US-China Co-Op Science Program, November 7, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Seminar on Urban Problems: US-China Co-Op Science Program, November 7, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Memorabilia From J. N. Warfield Trip to Taiwan, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Systems Engineering Systems Workshop Reference Materials at BSRC, February 1971 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - System Planning Guidelines for Improving Project Management for Ohio's Dept. of Education, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - A.I.D. Method Project at Battelle, [J.N. Warfield], undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Development of a Unified System Engineering Approach, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Planning to Meet Educational Needs in Ohio Schools, Summary Report Phase-1, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Battelle Presidents' Annual Reports & Other Brochures, 1966-1974 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Dept. of First Stories & Other Warfield Memorabilia, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Office Chronology Notebook at Startup of CIM, at UVA [J.N. Warfield], August 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - L'Espresso Magazine, Rome N.29 Anno XXIII 24, pp 670, August 1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - UVA Chair Dinner [J.N. Warfield], April 15 and 27, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Engineering Review, Article on System Engineering [J.N. Warfield], 1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - UVA Warfield Memorabilia Paper Clips [J.N. Warfield], 1975-1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - UVA Warfield Memorabilia & Newspaper Clippings [J.N. Warfield], 1975-1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - IBM Consulting [J.N. Warfield], 1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - COMSAT Labs Consulting Job, Washington D.C. [J.N. Warfield], 1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - COMSAT Labs Report, Washington D.C. [J.N. Warfield], 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - COMSAT Trip, Consulting Job, Washington D.C.[J.N. Warfield], June-July 1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - COMSAT Summer Consulting Job, Washington D.C. [J.N. Warfield], 1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Resumes & Biography [J.N. Warfield], 1964-1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Resumes & Biography [J.N. Warfield], Zeeman E.C. Catastrophe Theory, PP 65-83, June 27, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Recent Biographical Materials Prepared [J.N. Warfield], 1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - List of Classmates of J.N. Warfield at Penn State Univ., undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Photo of J.N. Warfield & H.I. Tarpley on Front Cover of Penn State Review, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Wilcox Electric Company, Directory of Company Employees, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Diplomas & Awards [J.N. Warfield], undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - PENNSTAC Instructions & Logical Design of a General Digital Computer for Education & Research [Robert William House], 1950 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Employment Records & Correspondence About Possible Jobs [J.N. Warfield], 1946-1963 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Nexus-Center for Interactive Management Newsletter, 1982-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - ISM Related Documents, V.1 & V.2 [J.N. Warfield], 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - ISM Development History Notes Jotted by Rose [J.N. Warfield], 1970-1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - ISM Related Documents, V.1 [J.N. Warfield], 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - ISM Related Documents, V.2, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - ISM Related Correspondence, Papers, Newsclippings, Proposals, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - ISM Related Correspondence, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Research History Papers V.7, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Symposium on Computer Assisted Analysis & Model Specification, Univ of Colorado, March 24, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - ISM Exercise at COMSAT & Miscellaneous Papers, [J.N. Warfield], undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - The S-P Chart & Caution Index,NEC Bulletin 80-1 [Takahiro Sato], October 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - An innovative Method For Developing Objective Tress & Its Applications, September 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Recent Psychometric Developments in Japan Educational Measurements Problems, at Urbana Champaign [Maurice M. Tatsuoka], undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Research Requests for ISM Related Documents, April 1980-April 1981 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Condensed Forms of Large Scale Models [Emilio Fontella, Edouard Rossier], 1979 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Research History Materials, V.5 [J.N. Warfield], 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Computer Graphics Aided Interpretive Structural Modeling a Tool for Conceptualizing Complex Design Problems [Fred Edward Langhorst], December 28, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Decision Theory & Design Methodology [James A. Wise], 1977 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - US-Australia CO-OP Science Program, Proposals for Joint Seminar, June 1977 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Research History Materials About ISM, V.4 [J.N. Warfield], 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Research History Materials, V.3 [J.N. Warfield], 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Goals Study for the Rodman Program UVA Report Empty, April 1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Modeling Management IEEE [J.N. Warfield], January 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - The Mathematics of Design [J.N. Warfield], June 9, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Reading Maps of Relations, Unit M-A of OBE Final Report V.2 [J.N. Warfield], 1980 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Workshop on Collective Inquiry Methods at Far West Labs, Presentation by J.N. Warfield, Summer 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Societal Systems Design Problems [J.N. Warfield], September 1980 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Priority Structures, IEEE Paper [J.N. Warfield], October 10, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - A Short Course in ISM at IEEE-SMC Conference, Boston [J.N. Warfield], October 1980 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Methods for Enhancing Group Productivity: A Talk Before the Executive Advisory Council School of Business, UNI [J.N. Warfield], November 14, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - A Role for Values in Educational System Design IEEE-ICCS Conference [J.N. Warfield], December 1980 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Workshop on Consensus Methodologies Presented to Sancst, Saudi Arabia [J.N. Warfield], December 13, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Translatable Language Systems for Systems Modeling & Design, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Grapholosis, the Trans-Disciplinary Language, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Design for the Future of Environmental Education: Energy Economy Ethics, USGPO/US Dept. of Education, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Learning Through Model Building [J.N. Warfield], 1981 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - A Brief Annotated Bibliography on Universities, February 4, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Improving Mathematics Instruction in the U.S. School, Great University, February 4, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Institutional Mechanics & The Great University [J.N. Warfield], 1981 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Science & Systems Science, a Technology Perspective, January 1980 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Mapping Environmental Education in Univ. of District of Columbia, August 1981 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - The Options Field Methodology for Design [J.N. Warfield], December 1981 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Current Thinking & Practice Concerning Decision Situation Rooms [J.N. Warfield], December 1981 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Consensus Methodologies, This Material was Published as Appendix to Book Article, September 1982 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Option Profile Method Excerpts With 3 Page Illustration Example, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Interpretive Structural Modeling in Olsen ED Group Planning [J.N. Warfield], 1982 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Symposium: Systems Methodology Applied to Government, SGSR, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - ISM: An Introduction to the Foundation, Methods& Applications of a Useful Idea [J.N. Warfield, Robert J. Waller, Maureen S., 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - ISM/Consensus Methodology Short course in Bonn, West Germany, Presentation by J.N. Warfield, April 1982 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - A Newspaper Clip About Amazon Jungle, Brazil, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - ISM, SIGMA-4 Process Workshop for IBM at Sao Paulo, Presentation by J.N. Warfield, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Organization & System Learning, Manuscript for 1983 Presentation, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - UVA Center Helps Management, Newspaper Clippings [J.N. Warfield], June 21, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Strategic Planning for Saudi Arabia: SIGMA Meetings & Consensus Methodologies, August 1982 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Book Review, The Thought of C.S. Peirce IEEE-SMC-12:5, September 1982 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Chronology Related to the Use of ISM [J.N. Warfield], 1982 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Digest of Annotated Bibliography on ISM [J.N. Warfield], June 1980 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Graphics for System Design, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Group Productivity, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Options Field /Option Profiles Method for top Down Design [J.N. Warfield], undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - How to Read the Maps Produced in ISM Process [J.N. Warfield], 1982 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Employment Correspondence, Job Hunting, Positions Held by J.N. Warfield, 1964-1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Employment Correspondence, Job Hunting, Positions Held by J.N. Warfield, 1964-1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Proposal to Conduct a Seminar in Australia on Improving the Educational Planning & Management, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Electronic Goniometer Patent Issued 1967 [J.N. Warfield, Gooch, Hogan], 1965-1969 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - IEEE Transactions on Aerospace & Electronic Systems, Lally, & Warfield, September 1966 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - A Method & Apparatus for Improving Spectral Purity of Transmitted Signals [J.N. Warfield], August 1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "Spurious Signal Amplitudes in High Frequency Transistor Mixers," [J.N. Warfield, Teddy R. Channel], November 1965 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - IEEE Conference Record on Switching Circuit Theory & Logical Design, Univ of Michigan, [J.N. Warfield], October 6, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "A Precision Electronic Goniometer," [J.N. Warfield, G.M. Gooch], 1965 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Corrective System for Minimizing Can-Dme Spurious Radiation, IEEE Trans on Aerospace & Navigational Electronics, March 1965 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Kansas Engineer: A Letter to a Scholar, November 1963 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Principles of Logic Design & Errata Sheets, [J.N. Warfield], 1965 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Answer Book to Introduction to Analog Computers, Manuscript Form in Acct Press Binder, 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - "A Digital Computer Program for Reducing Logical Statements to a Minimal Form," [John N. Warfield, Kenneth J. Butler], 1959 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Switching Circuits as Topological Models in Discrete Probability Theory, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Note on the Reduction of Switching Functions, ARC/AC, June 1958 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - How to Improve Systems Engineering, [J.N. Warfield], July 1957 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Optimum Diagnostic Sequences for Complex Systems, QIC Illinois, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - On the Design of a Creative Machine [J.N. Warfield], 1958 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - The Isolation & Correction of Computer Malfunctions, Ramo-Woodridge Corp., September 4, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Invariants in System Design, Ramo-Woolridge Corp., August 23, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Systems Engineering, A Report For Ordinance Research Lab [J.N. Warfield], August 10, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Synthesis of a Dynamically - Variable Electronic Filter, [J.N. Warfield, John G. Truxal], January 1953 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - A Table of Steady-State Transforms, [J.N. Warfield, D.L. Waidelich], 1953 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Mistakes of Omission & Commission, February 24, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - The Engineer as a Change Agent [J.N. Warfield], 1982 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Fundamentals of Sequential Machines, CIM Seminar Talk [J.N. Warfield], April 27, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Quality of Life Edicatopm, Paper by Bela Banathy, February 1981 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Zonal Diagnosis in Interactive Management, A One-Page Description of the Seven Consensus Methodologies, March 1982 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Consensus Methodologies, One Week Course Developed for Larry Edwards, March 1982 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - "Producing Useful Knowledge for Organization," A Summary Notes by J.N. Warfield, November 1982 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - "On the Future of Environmental Education," A Paper by J.N. Warfield at UNI, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Facilitator Hints, Handwritten [J.N. Warfield], 1983 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - A Preliminary Framework for Urban Model Building, Comments on B. Golden & A. Assad, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - University of Virginia II Annual Chair Dinner, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Modeling Large Scale Systems at National & Regional Levels," Workshop at Brookings Institution, February 1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - NSF Grants Extensions of ISM, Correspondence, Budget & Records, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Extension of ISM-NSF Grants Copy of Proposal, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Extensions of ISM Report to NSF on Research Grant, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Proposals for Improvement of Graduate Engineering Education, Correspondence with Exxon Education Foundation, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - ISM Session Details Correspondence With Clausden, Morgenwick on NSF Grants, May 1979 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence & Memos Regarding Asmusen Work at Minnesota, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence & Memos Regarding Anyiwo Work at Minnesota DNR, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence & Memos Regarding Anyiwo Work at Minnesota DNR & His Ph.D Work at UVA, December 18, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence & Memos Regarding Anyiwo Work at Minnesota DNR & Memo to Committee, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence & Memos Regarding Anyiwo Work at Minnesota, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - A Brief History of Mr. Anyiwo Involvement in Minnesota PEAT Resource Management, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Composite Summary of Committee Recommendations For Mr. Anyiwo on PEAT Resource Management, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - National Systems Center Workshop, NSF Sponsored Meeting at MIT, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - University of Virginia Catalog, J.N. Warfield on Graduate Faculty Roster Page 156, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - "An Interactive Methodologically Assisted Decision Making Facility, a Proposal by Andrew Sage, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - IBM Notes, Correspondence, Consulting Trips on ISM Work, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Participative Conceptual System Design Draft For NSF Proposal, October 1979 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Workshop in India With Bob House for TATA Company, Kirloskar & IEEE, December 1979 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Dean Gibson Annual Report at Provost, UVA, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - World Peace Futures Seminar Given by Gibson's Graduate Systems 501 Class at University of Virginia, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - S.W.I.I.S Workshop, Meeting Papers, Correspondence, Virginia, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Virginia Division of Forestry Papers & Reports, Related to CIM, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Description of Two UVA Systems Engineering Department Course Classes, May 1980 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Israel Institute of Technology Correspondence as Visiting Professor Dr. Jacob Bean, 19789-1979 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Office Chronology Notebook, Correspondence at UNI [J.N. Warfield], 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - UNI Center for Problem Solving, Proposal, Brochures & Literature on Equipment for Situation Rooms, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Papers Connected With Research Work at University of Northern Iowa, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Computer Curriculum at UNI Proposal by Univ of Northern Iowa, Department of Mathematics, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence Regarding Work Positions, Salary & Resignations at University of Virginia, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Newspaper Article About the Salaries of Univ. of Virginia, Employees Published in Daily Progress, July 1978 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - University of Virginia Official Appointment & Subsequent Addenda, 1973-1977 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Professional Activity Reports, Annual Report Turned Into UVA by Warfield, 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Department Faculty Letter of Commendation Sent to Dean Gibson, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - April Tenure & Promotion Policy Committee Report by Warfield & McVey, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Creating a Technological Plan for the Restructured College of Education, The Ohio State University, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - College of Education Technology Plan, January 1997 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Customer Satisfaction, End User Supported Services Europe, October 1996 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Report of the ARPA Workshops by Henry Albert, October 1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - SMC - Faculty Consulting Workshop, December 17, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - II Industrial Base Workshop Held by DSMC an IM Report, December 1990 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - DSMC Facility Design Workshop, October 1990 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - DSMC Facility Design Workshop, September 1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)